<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nathan McGinness</title>
    <link href="http://njmcgee.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://njmcgee.com/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-01T16:38:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://njmcgee.com/</id>
    
    
    <entry>
        <title>Please, please, please stop asking how to find a technical co-founder. &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.humbledmba.com/please-please-please-stop-asking-how-to-find"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/polishing-a-turd</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>And don&#8217;t say that you&#8217;re the idea guy. Having an idea is one piece, but it&#8217;s a very, very small piece.  In fact, it&#8217;s so small that it&#8217;s actually better to earn a technical co-founder without the idea in place so that you guys come up with it together. </blockquote>
<p>Excellent advice. It doesn’t matter if you’re looking for a co-founder, a designer, or even working with an agency. Your idea is useless until talented craftspeople get their hands on it. If you let them, they might be able to make it work. If you don’t, they are probably polishing a turd, and not enjoying the smell.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>OpenPhoto, a photo service for your S3 or Dropbox account &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jmathai/openphoto-a-photo-service-for-your-s3-or-dropbox-a"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/wheres-my-equity</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>When I see a very talented (and professionally proven) designer, writer or engineer asking for charity on Kickstarter I can’t help but feel that something is a bit whack &#8211; on two counts:</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> The creative (or arguably the entrepreneur in this case) is selling themselves short. We often see Kickstarters justifying the amount they are asking for by playing down any idea they will be paid and noting that the money will go towards bills, materials, etc. Why shouldn’t a talented creative, working on a project that people want be paid well!?</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> Where’s my equity? We are seeing start-up costs be funded without any exchange in return. What if Openphoto grows to the size of Flickr? The earliest of angels receive nothing for their investment (in some Kickstarter projects in the many thousands of dollars), or even a promise of being paid back.</p>
<p>I doubt this is the first software project on Kickstarter but it’s come right out of Sunnyvale, and an ex Yahoo/Flickr employee. There’s angel capital flying around The Bay Area at the moment &#8211; I can’t imagine being in a better place to access investors (big or small).</p>
<p>Somewhere there’s probably a line between personal creative projects, and professional or commercial endeavors. I’d suggest it’s somewhere between:</p>
<p>I need more wool so I can knit my grandchildren beautiful sweaters; and; I need $25,000 to bootstrap my new start-up for free.</p>
<p>That being said, I’m not against charitable behavior in creative projects, I understand there’s many without access to capital, and it seems that people want to give, so best of luck to all involved. I’m just confused about who is actually benefitting here.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Oxford Writing and Style Guide no longer recommending the Oxford comma &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://kottke.org/11/06/ditching-the-oxford-comma"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/the-kottke-style-guide</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Kottke on Oxford now recommending that internal documents ditch the serial/Oxford comma:</p>
<blockquote>The kottke.org style guide still advocates the use of the Oxford comma, but take that with a grain of salt; I also misuse semicolons, use too many (often unnecessary) parentheses &#8212; not to mention m-dashes that are actually rendered as two n-dashes in old-school <span class="caps">ASCII</span> fashion &#8212; use too many commas, and place punctuation outside quotation marks, which many people find, in the words of Bill S. Preston Esq. and Ted &#8220;Theodore&#8221; Logan, &#8220;bogus&#8221;.</blockquote>
<p>Funny stuff. If you get off on discussions about typographic structure and punctuation check out <a href="http://5by5.tv/talkshow/45">Episode #45 of the Talk Show</a> where Gruber and Benjamin discuss logical punctuation. I personally won’t defend Kottke’s use of “dumb quotes” but that’s maybe because pressing <code class="inline">alt + [</code> has become an ingrained behavior when writing a quotation.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Recent reads </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/recent-reads.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/recent-reads</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Syncing Instapaper and my Kindle has been one of the best moves I&#8217;ve made in a long time. I’m reading more of what I want to read, more often. Here’s what I&#8217;ve been reading lately.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/06/26/magazine/my-life-as-an-undocumented-immigrant.html?_r=2&amp;pagewanted=all">My Life as an Undocumented Immigrant</a> – Jose Antonio Vargas</h2>
<p>It’s unlikely you’ve missed this one, but if you have, it’s a great read. Jose Antonio Vargas, a well regarded journalist uncovers himself as an illegal immigrant the US, and explains how he did it.</p>
<h2><a href="http://marcdrummond.com/web-standards/2011/06/20/hell-bad-devices-responsive-web-design-and-web-standards">To hell with bad devices: Responsive web design and web standards</a> – Marc Drummond</h2>
<p>Marc Drummond against device specific design, urging us not to go to great lengths to support poor mobile browsers. IE6 haunted us for so long because we went to great lengths to support it. Let&#8217;s not repeat the same mistakes.</p>
<h2><a href="http://changeobserver.designobserver.com/feature/epiphany-of-an-ocean-swimmer/27548/">Epiphany of an Ocean Swimmer</a> – Barbara Flanagan</h2>
<p>I’ve never owned (or even worn) a wet-suit. I’m convinced it’s time to try.</p>
<h2><a href="http://observersroom.designobserver.com/alexandralange/post/new-apple-hq-1957/28018/">New Apple HQ, 1957</a> – Alexandra Lange</h2>
<p>Is Apple’s plan to build the perfect office building repeating corporate and architectural mistakes we’ve seen many times before? Is this a big missed opportunity for Cupertino?</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.phpied.com/overlooked-optimizations-images/">Overlooked Optimizations: Images</a> – Stoyan Stefanov</h2>
<p>We fuss about code-based front-end optimization, but often neglect our biggest bandwidth hog.</p>
<h2><a href="http://craigmod.com/journal/post_artifact/">Post-Artifact Books and Publishing</a> – Craig Mod</h2>
<p>Digital’s effect on how we produce, distribute and consume content, from one of the best thinkers in the space.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.cityofsound.com/blog/2011/06/on-retail.html">On retail</a> – Dan Hill</h2>
<p>A brilliant look at the current (rather poor) state of retail in Australia, the innovators elsewhere, and potential futures. It touches distribution patterns, fabrication, local economies and localism etc.</p>
<h2><a href="http://the99percent.com/tips/7034/Developing-Your-Creative-Practice-Tips-from-Brian-Eno">Developing Your Creative Practice: Tips from Brian Eno</a> – Scott McDowell</h2>
<p>Exactly as the title says.</p>
<h2><a href="http://observatory.designobserver.com/feature/standard-deviations-types-and-families-in-contemporary-design/26428/">Standard Deviations: Types and Families in Contemporary Design</a> – Paul Shaw</h2>
<p>An interesting critique on the typefaces MoMA selected to feature and add their collection.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Slow motion never gets old </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/slo-mo-never-gets-old.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/slo-mo-never-gets-old</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>(via <a href="http://kottke.org/11/06/slo-mo-cymbal-strike">Kottke</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Native style momentum scrolling to arrive in iOS 5 &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://johanbrook.com/browsers/native-momentum-scrolling-ios-5/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/native-style-momentum-scrolling-to-arrive-in-ios-5</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>It’s great news and more evidence that Apple are willing to lead the way in mobile browser development. <code class="inline">position: fixed</code> and <code class="inline">overflow: scroll</code> are also on their way with iOS 5, but let’s not get excited until Android catches up. Until these handsets enable position fixing and full overflow support we’ll have no choice but to continue to add JavaScript to fake these behaviors.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Topguest on your smartphone </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/topguest-on-your-smartphone.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/topguest-on-your-smartphone</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/topguest-mobile.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>I’ve been working on a mobile optimized version of Topguest and it went live today. Visit <a href="http://topguest.com">topguest.com</a> on your smartphone to take a look.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Project Spartan - Facebook’s Hush-Hush Plan To Take On Apple On Their Own Turf &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/15/facebook-project-spartan/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/project-spartan</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>I’m not sure I buy into this ‘build in the browser to fuck with Apple’ idea. <a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/">Steve Jobs evangelizes HTML5 and standards-based development</a> and Apple backs this up by building the the best available mobile browser (which is probably the exact reason Facebook are working with it).</p>
<p>Let’s say Facebook succeeds with “Project Spartan” and becomes a distribution centre for browser based applications. I doubt Apple would be upset by Facebook (a company with unrivaled reach) showcasing the capabilities of Apple’s mobile products. I also doubt that people will stop developing native Apple applications.</p>
<p>If this is a war, it requires Apple to be against the evolution of browser-based application development. I don’t think they are. I think the quality of their browsers is evidence enough for now.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Facebook Analog Research Laboratory </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/facebook-analog-research.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/facebook-analog-research</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/facebook.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>I recently stumbled across the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Facebook-Analog-Research-Laboratory/152917571386966">Facebook Analog Research Laboratory</a>  and I’m really impressed. Working as a designer at a software start-up (if we can call Facebook one) doesn’t usually provoke images of ink, paint, raw materials and hardware.</p>
<p>Although it’s clear that Facebook are currently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/04/27/facebook-acq-hires-daytum/">working to acquire</a> (and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/09/facebook-sofa/">here</a>) a world class design team, most wouldn’t think of Facebook&#8217;s crisp and minimal design ethos as one that includes decorative practice and paint spills.</p>
<p>It turns out that Facebook (like any big company) use printed materials and physical artifacts for a variety of reasons – events in particular. Outsourcing is expensive, and I’m not just talking about the printing bills, but the administration, the transportation and timing logistics, processing the purchase orders and invoices etc.</p>
<p>Facebook are both saving money, and speeding up the production process. Need some signage for a developer event <em>tonight</em>? Why not design, print and construct them &#8211; right now! It allows the same flexibility and agility we strive to give developers in a start-up environment.</p>
<p>I’m yet to meet a designer that doesn&#8217;t love paper, raw materials and the workshop environment. A workshop like this must also help in attracting (or closing the deal with) versatile design candidates.</p>
<p>But best of all, it encourages, engages, develops and nurtures the companies’ creatives.</p>
<p>Need evidence? <a href="http://www.underconsideration.com/fpo/archives/2011/05/president-barack-obama-at-facebook-tickets.php"><span class="caps">FPO</span></a> profiles the tickets the Facebook team produced in less than 24 for Obama&#8217;s Town Hall event at Facebook’s headquarters.</p>
<p><img src="/images/posts/tickets.jpg" style="margin-left: 0;" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/video/video.php?v=10150096693006777&amp;oid=75877461389&amp;comments">Take a video tour of the Facebook Analog Research Laboratory</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Walt Disney's MultiPlane Camera </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/disneys-multiplane-camera.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/disneys-multiplane-camera</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Innovation and execution. I think I’ll stop in at <a href="http://www.lostweekendvideo.com">Lost Weekend</a> and grab some Goofy cartoons.</p>
<p>(via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2011/06/14/walt-disney-animation">Daring Fireball</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Fixed positions with JavaScript </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/fixed-positions-with-javascript.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/fixed-positions-with-javascript</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Fixed elements (sidebars in particular) are <a href="http://help.bigcartel.com/articles/22-javascript-ajax">becoming</a> <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/configure/MC723LL/A?mco=MjEyOTY4OTQ">popular</a>. You know those sidebars that wait until the top of window hits them, and they magically stick?</p>
<p>In simple situations (this site for example) <span class="caps">CSS</span> will do the trick. But what if dynamic content at the top of your page changes this calculation (a flash or notification message for example)? Or your header likes to change size?</p>
<p><a href="http://ozanonay.com">Ozan</a> helped me solve this problem, and I thought I&#8217;d share.</p>
<p>We’ll start by selecting said element, calling our custom function, and specifying how far from the top of the page it lives:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="js"><span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;#fixed&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">myFixture</span><span class="p">({</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="mi">20</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre>
</div><p>And our function looks something like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="js"><span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">fn</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">myFixture</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">each</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    
    <span class="c1">// default css declaration </span>
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">elem</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">css</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;position&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;fixed&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
    
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">setPosition</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>         
      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">top</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
      <span class="c1">// get no of pixels hidden above the the window     </span>
      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">scrollTop</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">window</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">scrollTop</span><span class="p">();</span>    
      <span class="c1">// get elements distance from top of window</span>
      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">topBuffer</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">topBoundary</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">-</span> <span class="nx">scrollTop</span><span class="p">);</span>
      <span class="c1">// update position if required</span>
      <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">topBuffer</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">top</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="nx">topBuffer</span> <span class="p">}</span>
      <span class="nx">elem</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">css</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;top&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">top</span><span class="p">);</span>      
    <span class="p">};</span>
        
    <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">window</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">bind</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;scroll&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">setPosition</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="nx">setPosition</span><span class="p">();</span>
  <span class="p">});</span>
<span class="p">};</span>
</code></pre>
</div><p>Let’s revisit our first block of code, and base the calculation on the height of a header element above it:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="js"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">header</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;header&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">header</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">outerHeight</span><span class="p">();</span>
<span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;#fixed&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">myFixture</span><span class="p">({</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre>
</div><p>Another (even more flexible) approach would be to make <code class="default-size">topBoundary</code> equal to the <code class="default-size">.offset.top()</code> of the <code class="default-size">#fixed</code> element on load.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Topguest at Lake Tahoe </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/topguest-at-lake-tahoe.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/topguest-at-lake-tahoe</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/tahoe-01.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>The Topguest team took some friends to Lake Tahoe the weekend before last. As you can see, it’s a really beautiful part of the world.</p>
<p><img style="margin-left: 0;" src="/images/posts/tahoe-02.jpg"/><br />
<img style="margin-left: 0; margin-top: 30px" src="/images/posts/tahoe-03.jpg"/></p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A blog in two days with Jekyll &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://blog.topguest.com/2011/04/designing-and-building-a-blog-in-two-days.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/a-blog-in-two-days-with-jekyll</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>A post I wrote over at the Topguest blog on rapid blog development with <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki">Jekyll</a> &ndash; the same platform I built this blog with. If you’re interested in front-end development I think it’s worth a read.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Google drops IE7 &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2011/06/our-plans-to-support-modern-browsers.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/google-drops-ie7</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Great news. As of August 1st Google Apps (including gmail and docs) will drop support for IE7. If Google can do it, so can I.</p>
<blockquote>“As the world moves more to the web, these new browsers are more than just a modern convenience, they are a necessity for what the future holds.”</blockquote>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Anni Albers in the NGA online archive &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://cs.nga.gov.au/Search.cfm?mystartrow=1&realstartrow=1&VIEW_SELECT=1&CREIRN=12177&ORDER_SELECT=1&SHOWROWS=20"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/anni-albers</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/anni-albers.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>Have found some simply stunning Anni Albers (the wife of my favourite artist, Josef Albers) prints at the National Gallery Of Australia.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A new Topguest </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/05/a-new-topguest.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/05/a-new-topguest</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/topguest-devices.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>You might have noticed that things are changing at Topguest. A new design, some subtle but important changes to the application, and we’ve just launched the beginnings of a new mobile web experience.</p>
<p>One of the more dramatic changes is the much brighter color scheme. After applying it to some important layouts I mentioned to the team that we’d “turned the lights on”. This stuck with me, as I worked through problems unrelated to color or shade, and I hope it shows. We hope the new (and upcoming) changes, bring clarity, ease of use, and lots more points!</p>
<p>Things aren’t slowing anytime soon. We’re adding programs and new locations every day, and be sure to visit <a href="http://topguest.com">http://topguest.com</a> on your mobile browser. We’re regularly adding mobile optimized functionality so you can manage your points, and find locations on the go.</p>
<p>Any feedback? <a href="mailto:nathan@topguest.com">Get in touch</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Our vision for the future of loyalty &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://blog.topguest.com/2011/05/the-future-of-loyalty.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/05/the-future-of-loyalty</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Our <span class="caps">CEO</span> Geoff on the business we do at Topguest.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
</feed>