<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Nathan McGinness</title>
    <link href="http://njmcgee.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://njmcgee.com/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-20T18:17:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://njmcgee.com/</id>
    
    
    <entry>
        <title>Thomas Fournier &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://tomartichaut.blogspot.com/2011/04/blog-post_14.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-09-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/09/thomas-fournier</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/thomas.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>by <a href="http://tomartichaut.blogspot.com/">Thomas Fournier</a></p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>jQuery Overtakes Flash on World’s Top Websites &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://appendto.com/jquery-overtakes-flash"/>
        
        <updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/09/jquery-overtakes-flash</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p><span class="caps">DENVER</span>, Co. Aug. 24, 2011 – appendTo, the company dedicated to jQuery, the world’s most popular JavaScript Library, released data today showing that the percentage of websites that have jQuery deployed has officially surpassed the percentage of websites that have Adobe Flash deployed. Statistics compiled by <a href="http://httparchive.org"><span class="caps">HTTP</span> Archive</a>, which analyze the world’s top 17,000 websites, show that 48 percent of the sites use jQuery, while 47 percent use Flash.</p>
</blockquote>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Facebook’s Design Strategy &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://designmind.frogdesign.com/articles/facebook-s-design-strategy-a-status-update.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/09/facebooks-design-strategy</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Design is such an influential part of Facebook’s strategy that Cox and 64 other members of the design staff occupy desks that form a U-shape around founder and <span class="caps">CEO</span> Mark Zuckerberg.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Expands on some of my previous posts on Facebook&#8217;s design strategy. The more I think about it, the more I wonder if Facebook’s business provides the scope for roughly 64 designers (many of whom are absolutely brilliant) to all be at their best?</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Should designers code? </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/09/should-designers-code.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/09/should-designers-code</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p><a href="http://blog.frankchimero.com/post/9594863189">Frank Chimero</a> and <a href="http://andyrutledge.com/web-design-is-product-design.php">Andy Rutledge</a> recently answered this question with a big fat <b><span class="caps">YES</span></b>.</p>
<p>I completely agree. You don’t get to call yourself a web designer if you’re illiterate in <span class="caps">HTML</span> &amp; <span class="caps">CSS</span> (let’s not get bogged down in whether this is ‘coding’ or not). The discussion seems to come around regularly and it’s amazing that there is actual resistance to this idea (see <a href="http://andyrutledge.com/web-design-is-product-design.php">Rutledge’s article</a> for a succinct rebuttal).</p>
<p>But why do people resist this idea? Do they think markup and <span class="caps">CSS</span> is hard? Set in their ways? Scared it might be a slippery slope into nerdom?</p>
<p>If you’re brilliant enough to design beautiful websites you’ve already spent years mastering typography, composition, content strategy, visual design techniques, and some very complex tools. Learning <span class="caps">HTML</span> &amp; <span class="caps">CSS</span> is a piece of cake in comparison. You’ve got no excuse, you’re obviously smart enough and you’re lucky. With HTML5, CSS3, modern browsers, <a href="http://github.com">Github</a>, <a href="http://sass-lang.com/"><span class="caps">SASS</span></a> &amp; <a href="http://compass-style.org/">Compass</a> it’s not just easy – it’s fun.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Dear Loser &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/2011/09/dear-loser.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-09-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/09/dear-loser</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/dear-loser.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>via <a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/2011/09/dear-loser.html">Letters of Note</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The evolution of the web &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://evolutionofweb.appspot.com/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/09/evolution-of-the-web</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/evolution.png"></img>
          
          <p>Interactive visualization featuring screenshots of each major browser release.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Web Design is Product Design &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://andyrutledge.com/web-design-is-product-design.php"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/web-design-is-product-design</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Debate is usually an indication of intelligent human pursuit. But not always. One issue for design students—this no-brainer, simplest of issues—has ever been kept alive within the inane realm of debate since it first arose. As such, it is an unflattering indictment on those who contest the simple fact that a web designer must craft markup and css.</p>
</blockquote>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>UXUI UXUI &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://uxuiuxui.tumblr.com/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/uxui-uxui</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/uxui.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>Good, bad and interesting. Get your daily dose of <a href="http://uxuiuxui.tumblr.com/"><span class="caps">UXUI</span> <span class="caps">UXUI</span></a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Old S.F. &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.oldsf.org/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/old-sf</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/library.png"></img>
          
          <p><a href="http://www.oldsf.org/">Old SF</a> is an amazing location-based collection of archived photos around San Francisco. <a href="http://blog.iso50.com/25262/marina-branch-library-x-old-sf/">ISO50 found these great photos of the Marina Branch Library.</a></p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Ease up on the all-caps &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://littlebigdetails.com/post/9417762507/getsatisfaction-gives-instant-feedback-when"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/ease-up-on-the-all-caps</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/getsatisfaction.png"></img>
          
          <p>Thoughtful, fun design. <a href="http://littlebigdetails.com/">Little Big Details</a> is great.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Actelion Imagery Wizard &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.onformative.com/work/actelion-imagery-wizard/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/onformative-generative-branding</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p><a href="http://www.onformative.com/">Onformative</a>, a Berlin based generative design studio (in their own words) use <a href="http://processing.org">Processing</a> to build an damn slick image generation tool as part of a comprehensive branding job.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Faraway &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.playfaraway.com/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/faraway</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p><a href="http://www.toucheliss.com/">Eliss</a> is an oldie but a goodie, and my favorite iOS game. The game made early and perfect use of the multitouch surface, had an incredibly focused and beautiful aesthetic vision, and an addictive generative quality. Steph Thirion, the genius behind it has a teaser for his new game, <a href="http://www.playfaraway.com/">Faraway</a>. I’ve got a feeling the audiovisual overlap is to feature even more strongly, can’t wait.</p>
<blockquote>
I made a video teaser for my upcoming game Faraway.<br/>
Cool fact: it was all made in code, it’s an uncut programming sequence. No video editors were used.<br/>
- The game will come out this fall on iOS. Specific date and platform are <span class="caps">TBA</span>.
</blockquote>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Glass Beach &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://thisiscolossal.com/2011/08/glass-beach/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/glass-beach</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/glass-beach.jpg"></img>
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>During the early 20th century residents of Fort Bragg, California chose to dispose of their waste by hurling it off the cliffs above a beach. No object was too toxic or too large as household appliances, automobiles, and all matter of trash were tossed into the crashing waves below, eventually earning it the name The Dumps. In 1967 the North Coast Water Quality Board closed the area completely and initiated a series of cleanups to slowly reverse decades of pollution and environmental damage. But there was one thing too costly (or perhaps impossible) to tackle: the millions of tiny glass shards churning in the surf. Over time the unrelenting ocean waves have, in a sense, cleansed the beach, turning the sand into a sparkling, multicolored bed of smooth glass stones now known as Glass Beach</blockquote>
<p>(via <a href="http://thisiscolossal.com/2011/08/glass-beach/">Colossal</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Recent reads 3 </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/08/recent-reads-3.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/recent-reads-3</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <h2><a href="http://zachholman.com/posts/how-github-works/">How GitHub Works</a> – Zach Holman</h2>
<p>A developer at Github gets straight to the point with quotes like, “Hours are Bullshit”, and “Meetings are fucking toxic”.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/08/15/opinion/stop-coddling-the-super-rich.html?_r=3&amp;src=tp&amp;smid=fb-share&amp;pagewanted=all">Stop Coddling the Super-Rich</a> – Warren E. Buffett</h2>
<p>Now here’s some perspective. Buffett publicly declares how much income tax he paid last year ($6,938,744, 17.4% of his taxable income) and explains why it’s not enough.</p>
<h2><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111904007304576499220914732798.html?mod=wsj_share_tweet">The Man Who Got Us to &#8216;Like&#8217; Everything</a> – Geoffrey Fowler</h2>
<p>An interview with Soleio Cuervo, the man behind the ubiquitous thumbs-up icon (now on 2.5 million other sites). My favorite quote:<blockquote>If a design—even one that took months to create—isn&#8217;t working, Facebook <span class="caps">CEO</span> Mark Zuckerberg will toss it out entirely. &#8220;It is nerve-wracking for new designers,&#8221; said Mr. Cuervo. &#8220;I think of the stuff we do [as being] like building sand castles.&#8221;</blockquote></p>
<h2><a href="http://bhorowitz.com/2011/08/08/the-fine-line-between-fear-and-courage/">The Fine Line Between Fear and Courage</a> – Ben Horowitz</h2>
<p>On the difference between the hard correct decision and the easy wrong decision.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.fastcodesign.com/1664704/the-creator-of-ted-aims-to-reinvent-conferences-once-again">The Creator Of <span class="caps">TED</span> Aims To Reinvent Conferences Once Again</a> – Warren Berger</h2>
<p>Richard Saul Wurman the original founder of <a href="http://www.ted.com/"><span class="caps">TED</span></a> has a new formula for the 21st century conference. Ignore the wankery (like “intellectual jazz”) and it might have some promise.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.grantland.com/story/_/id/6763000/bad-decisions">Bad Decisions</a> – Chuck Klosterman</h2>
<p>Klosterman argues that Breaking Bad is superior to Mad Men, The Sopranos, and The Wire. A well considered piece about the only TV shows worth talking about.</p>
<h2><a href="http://andyrutledge.com/journalism.php">Journalism</a> – Andy Rutledge</h2>
<p>Rutledge’s <a href="http://andyrutledge.com/news-redux.php">redesign of the NY Times website</a> caused quite a stir. Unfortunately it seems many of his critics failed to read the article. They not only missed his main point, that digital news is broken, but failed to even critique the design itself. Khoi Vinh (previous design director at the NY Times) <a href="http://www.subtraction.com/2011/07/28/unsolicited-redesigns">gives a fairly balanced reply</a> but it’s disappointing that it turned into a discussion about unsolicited redesigns rather than how we can improve online news, which I’d agree needs a thorough re-think.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.subtraction.com/2011/08/17/in-defense-of-client-services">In Defense of Client Services</a> – Khoi Vinh</h2>
<p>Vinh takes a small step back after declaring <a href="http://www.subtraction.com/2011/07/20/the-end-of-client-services">The End of Client Servies</a>. No arguments, companies will continue to need hired guns (design expertise) but the digital agency that continues to use an almost completely irrelevant advertising agency model does so at their own peril.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Problem with All-Star Teams &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.appleoutsider.com/2011/08/03/ball/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/the-problem-with-all-star-teams</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s gobbling up a remarkable amount of talent — an All-Star Team, if you will. The problem with all-star rosters, of course, is that as a team they often suck. It’s an odd phenomenon, but if you put too much greatness in the same room, things don’t always turn out so… great.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Matt Drance wonders if Facebook are taking a risk by putting too much talent in the same room. It’s an odd concern. A individual doesn’t need talent to ruin a good team (but ego might help). This all boils down to the individuals involved and Facebook’s ability to give their brilliant new talent scope and room to work. One thing is for sure, you don’t lower your recruitment standards out of a superstitious belief that an “All-Star team” is going to fail.</p>
<p>To be fair, the article acknowledges this and the leadership challenges involved, but ends by wondering if Facebook can replicate Apple’s design driven success. Why an Apple (or Steve Jobs) comparison is necessary I’m not sure,  but seeing important companies put such great value in design is encouraging to see – no need for alarm bells.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Lucas Simões &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lucsa/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/lucas-simoes</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/lucas-simoes.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>São Paulo based architect and artist Lucas Simões produces portraits by making cuts in layered photographs. (via <a href="http://thisiscolossal.com/2011/08/new-work-from-lucas-simoes/">Quipsologies</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Push Pop Press acquired by Facebook &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://pushpoppress.com/about/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/08/push-pop-press-acquired-by-facebook</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Now we&#8217;re taking our publishing technology and everything we&#8217;ve learned and are setting off to help design the world&#8217;s largest book, Facebook.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Facebook continue to build what might become an unrivaled web design team (see <a href="http://www.madebysofa.com/blog/facebook-acquires-sofa/">here</a> and <a href="http://daytum.wordpress.com/2011/04/27/moving-west/">here</a>) and <a href="http://localhost:4000/2011/06/facebook-analog-research.html">facility</a>.</p>
<p>Great for the hundreds of of millions of Facebook users (and any future Facebook iPad offerings), although it’s a little sad we won’t get to see Push Pop improve on their brilliant work thus far.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The End of Client Services &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.subtraction.com/2011/07/20/the-end-of-client-services"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/the-end-of-client-services</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Basically, I came to the conclusion that if I wanted to design great user experiences then that old model of being a design contractor or a studio or an agency would not work. Instead, it’s necessary to be a part of the company that owns the product, to be in a position where I can continually work on and improve the product without the artificial constraints of a services contract.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.subtraction.com/about">Khoi Vinh</a>, the author of popular design blog <a href="http://www.subtraction.com">Subtraction</a>, previous Design Director for the NY Times, and previous founder of a design studio reflects on his recent decision to start his own company (more info on that is said to be coming soon).</p>
<p>Anyone who has worked in a digital studio will empathize with Vinh’s story. A team puts great work into the first iteration of a product only to see the money dry up, the contract end, and a product neglected when it most needs love  &#8211; after real users get their hands on it!</p>
<p>Well written piece, and a nice (perhaps a little more considered) follow-up to <a href="http://pieratt.tumblr.com/post/7537191978/dear-graphic-and-web-designers-please-understand-that">Ben Pieratt&#8217;s recent article</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Recent reads 2 </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/07/recent-reads-2.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/recent-reads-2</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <h2><a href="http://heathenscripture.wordpress.com/2011/07/14/you-shut-your-goddamn-carbon-taxin-mouth/">You shut your goddamn carbon-taxin’ mouth</a> – Geoff Lemon</h2>
<p>A nice bit of perspective as Australia debates a price on carbon.</p>
<h2><a href="http://charliepark.org/slopegraphs/">Edward Tufte’s “Slopegraphs”</a> – Charlie Park</h2>
<p>For the data visualization people out there. Park searches for and analyzes visualizations that take the form of Tufte’s rarely adopted “slopegraph”.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/07/03/technology/03ping.html?_r=1">Silicon Valley Culture, but in San Francisco?</a> – Damon Darlin</h2>
<p>The City of San Francisco has provided Twitter with massive tax-breaks to keep them in the city, and hopefully rejuvenate a blighted area of the Tenderloin. Are the tax breaks going to do much good if the employees enjoy catered lunches, private gyms, and rarely leave their office?</p>
<h2><a href="http://m.runofplay.com/2011/07/02/keep-calm-and-carry-on/">Keep Calm and Carry On</a> – Alexandra Lange</h2>
<p>You don’t need to be a soccer fan to enjoy this one, if you enjoy excellent sports writing, here’s a brilliant example.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.gavinelliott.co.uk/2011/07/the-healthy-future-of-the-web-industry-maybe-short-lived/">The healthy future of the web industry maybe short-lived</a> – Gavin Elliott</h2>
<p>It’s clear that that educational institutions aren’t even close to keeping up with the demands of the internet industry. Elliott starts to consider what this might mean for our industry in the long term. For further reading see <a href="http://www.andyrutledge.com/the-ux-design-education-scam.php">The UX Design Education Scam</a> by <a href="http://andyrutledge.com/">Andy Rutledge</a>.</p>
<h2><a href="http://adgrok.com/why-founding-a-three-person-startup-with-zero-revenue-is-better-than-working-for-goldman-sachs/">Why founding a three-person startup with zero revenue is better than working for Goldman Sachs.</a> – Antonio</h2>
<p>Says little about working for a start-up, but an interesting and rather scathing insight into working on Wall Street.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.good.is/post/how-violent-sex-helped-ease-my-ptsd/">I’m Gonna Need You to Fight Me On This: How Violent Sex Helped Ease My <span class="caps">PTSD</span></a> – Mac McClelland</h2>
<p>An intense autobiographical piece of journalism. The story starts in Haiti, one year after the the “earthquake that shook the country into ugly chaos.” Also see <a href="http://jezebel.com/5817381/female-journalists--researchers-respond-to-haiti-ptsd-article">this response</a> from a group of female journalists and researchers who have lived and worked in Haiti.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1762632/telling-the-story-a-qa-on-leadership-with-john-lilly">How An Introverted Engineer Came Out Of His Shell To Lead Mozilla</a> – Kermit Pattison</h2>
<p>Exactly as the title says.</p>
<h2><a href="http://regardingwork.com/2011/07/17/hierarchies-kill/">Hierarchies Kill</a> – Ash Fontana</h2>
<p>Advice for keeping your company “flat” (<a href="http://www.inc.com/magazine/20110401/jason-fried-why-i-run-a-flat-company.html">as written about</a> by Jason Fried of <a href="http://37signals.com/">37signals</a>). For further reading see <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/boss.html">You weren’t meant to have a boss</a> by <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/index.html">Paul Graham</a>.</p>
<h2><a href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/07/07/a-walk-in-the-woods-with-mark-zuckerberg/">A Walk in the Woods With Mark Zuckerberg</a> – Nick Bilton</h2>
<p>Ever imagined going on a romantic walk in the woods with world’s richest man under 30? It could happen.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Dear Graphic and Web Designers, please understand that there are greater opportunities available to you. &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://pieratt.tumblr.com/post/7537191978/dear-graphic-and-web-designers-please-understand-that"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/dear-designers</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>
<p>Your press checks are bullshit<br />
Your personal logo is bullshit<br />
Your employer is bullshit<br />
Your studio is bullshit</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A bold article by <a href="http://pieratt.com/">Ben Pieratt</a> from <a href="http://svpply.com">Svpply</a> on why designers might want to reconsider their careers.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Peoplemovin - Migration flows across the world &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.peoplemov.in/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/peoplemovin-migration-flows</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/migrants.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>People Movin by Carlo Zapponi is an interactive graph that displays migration patterns. It’s simple, but incredibly rich and impressively built with Canvas/HTML5.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Steve Lambert’s brilliant &amp; awkward 404 page &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://visitsteve.com/404.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/steve-lamberts-brilliant-404</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>The awkwardness, ambiguity and near uselessness of the 404 page.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Bad design? </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/07/design.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/design</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>I couldn’t believe my eyes. Who designed this evil (but kinda fun looking) death trap?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.quora.com/Design/What-is-the-worst-piece-of-design-ever-done">What is the worst piece of design ever done?</a> on <a href="http://www.quora.com">Quora</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Boom or bubble? &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="/images/big-boom.jpg"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/boom-or-bubble</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/big-boom-small.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>Impressive infographics comparing recent data to that of the the late 90’s. Some of the more interesting pieces of data:</p>
<ul>
	<li>Venture investment peaked in the 1st quarter of 2000 at $27 billion</li>
	<li>Current investment looks to be around the $6 billion mark</li>
</ul>
<ul>
	<li>A total of 619 tech IPOs in 1998, 1999 and 2000.</li>
	<li>A total of 84 tech IPOs in 2009, 2010 and 2011.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
	<li>The current number of active Facebook users is equal to the number of total internet users in 2002.</li>
	<li>The current number of iPhone owners is equal to the number of total internet users in 1997.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
	<li>Current revenue multipliers look quite high. Facebook at 37.5x ($75 billion valuation at $2 billion revenue), Zynga at 40x ($10 billion valuation at $850 million revenue), Twitter at 55x ($8.5 billion valuation at $150 million revenue).</li>
</ul>
<p>Designed by <a href="http://www.kissmetrics.com/">Kissmetrics</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>DesignersMX &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://designers.mx/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/more-mixtapes</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/more-mixtapes.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>More mixtapes! <a href="http://designers.mx/">DesignersMX</a> invites designers to submit a mix and design an accompanying cover. Listening to <a href="http://designers.mx/patterns_process/">Patterns and Process</a> at the moment, purely because I liked the cover. Good mix though.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Illuminated Mixtapes &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://gigawattdesign.com/tunes/index.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/illuminated-mixtapes</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/mixtape.jpg"></img>
          
          <p><a href="http://gigawattdesign.com/tunes/index.html">Adam Parks</a> has put together 20 wonderful mixtapes, illustrating a cover for each. (via <a href="http://www.subtraction.com/2011/07/07/the-illuminated-mixtapes?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+subtraction+Subtraction">Subtraction</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Ridiculous Pool Paint Attack </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/07/skate-paint.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/skate-paint</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/skate-paint.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>Always love these sort of generative processes brought into the physical. Complete with paint, real mess, even stacks and grinds. Check out the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ScW5kWzSaSI&amp;feature=player_embedded#at=25">making-of video</a>. (via <a href="http://thisiscolossal.com/2011/07/the-ridiculous-pool-spraypaint-skateboarding/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+colossal+%28Colossal%29">Colossal</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Lego Architecture - Falling Water &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://architecture.lego.com/en-us/Products/architect/21005%20-%20Fallingwater.aspx"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/falling-waters-lego</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/fallingwater.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>I want. <a href="http://architecture.lego.com/en-us/Products/architect/21004%20-%20Guggenheim.aspx">The Guggenheim Museum</a>, <a href="http://architecture.lego.com/en-us/Products/Architect/21008%20-%20Burj%20Khalifa.aspx">Burj Khalifa</a> and <a href="http://architecture.lego.com/en-us/Products/Architect/21009%20-%20Farnsworth%20House.aspx">The Farnsworth House</a> also available.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Porn star meets architecture porn </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/07/architecture-porn.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/architecture-porn</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Filmed at Lautner’s famous Chemosphere House. If you like the building find yourself a copy of <a href="http://www.infinitespacethemovie.com/">Infinite Space</a>, a wonderful documentary on Lautner’s work (including this building). If you like Sasha Grey I don’t think you’ll need my help finding more of her.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Austin Madison on creativity </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/07/austin-madison-on-creativity.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/austin-madison-on-creativity</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/letter01.jpg"></img>
          
          <p><img src="/images/posts/letter02.jpg" style="margin-left: 0;" /></p>
<p>Via <a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/2011/07/persist.html">Letters of Note</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Amon Tobin 'ISAM' Live (Extended Trailer) </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/07/amon-tobin-isam.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/amon-tobin-isam</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>The power of collaboration. Would love to see this in person.</p>
<p>(via <a href="http://blog.iso50.com/24597/amon-tobin-isam/">ISO50</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Please, please, please stop asking how to find a technical co-founder. &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.humbledmba.com/please-please-please-stop-asking-how-to-find"/>
        
        <updated>2011-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/07/polishing-a-turd</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <div class="clear"></div>
<blockquote>And don&#8217;t say that you&#8217;re the idea guy. Having an idea is one piece, but it&#8217;s a very, very small piece.  In fact, it&#8217;s so small that it&#8217;s actually better to earn a technical co-founder without the idea in place so that you guys come up with it together. </blockquote>
<p>Excellent advice. It doesn’t matter if you’re looking for a co-founder, a designer, or even working with an agency. Your idea is useless until talented craftspeople get their hands on it. If you let them, they might be able to make it work. If you don’t, they are probably polishing a turd, and not enjoying the smell.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>OpenPhoto, a photo service for your S3 or Dropbox account &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/jmathai/openphoto-a-photo-service-for-your-s3-or-dropbox-a"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/wheres-my-equity</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>When I see a very talented (and professionally proven) designer, writer or engineer asking for charity on Kickstarter I can’t help but feel that something is a bit whack &#8211; on two counts:</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> The creative (or arguably the entrepreneur in this case) is selling themselves short. We often see Kickstarters justifying the amount they are asking for by playing down any idea they will be paid and noting that the money will go towards bills, materials, etc. Why shouldn’t a talented creative, working on a project that people want be paid well!?</p>
<p><strong>2.</strong> Where’s my equity? We are seeing start-up costs be funded without any exchange in return. What if Openphoto grows to the size of Flickr? The earliest of angels receive nothing for their investment (in some Kickstarter projects in the many thousands of dollars), or even a promise of being paid back.</p>
<p>I doubt this is the first software project on Kickstarter but it’s come right out of Sunnyvale, and an ex Yahoo/Flickr employee. There’s angel capital flying around The Bay Area at the moment &#8211; I can’t imagine being in a better place to access investors (big or small).</p>
<p>Somewhere there’s probably a line between personal creative projects, and professional or commercial endeavors. I’d suggest it’s somewhere between:</p>
<p>I need more wool so I can knit my grandchildren beautiful sweaters; and; I need $25,000 to bootstrap my new start-up for free.</p>
<p>That being said, I’m not against charitable behavior in creative projects, I understand there’s many without access to capital, and it seems that people want to give, so best of luck to all involved. I’m just confused about who is actually benefitting here.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Oxford Writing and Style Guide no longer recommending the Oxford comma &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://kottke.org/11/06/ditching-the-oxford-comma"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/the-kottke-style-guide</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Kottke on Oxford now recommending that internal documents ditch the serial/Oxford comma:</p>
<blockquote>The kottke.org style guide still advocates the use of the Oxford comma, but take that with a grain of salt; I also misuse semicolons, use too many (often unnecessary) parentheses &#8212; not to mention m-dashes that are actually rendered as two n-dashes in old-school <span class="caps">ASCII</span> fashion &#8212; use too many commas, and place punctuation outside quotation marks, which many people find, in the words of Bill S. Preston Esq. and Ted &#8220;Theodore&#8221; Logan, &#8220;bogus&#8221;.</blockquote>
<p>Funny stuff. If you get off on discussions about typographic structure and punctuation check out <a href="http://5by5.tv/talkshow/45">Episode #45 of the Talk Show</a> where Gruber and Benjamin discuss logical punctuation. I personally won’t defend Kottke’s use of “dumb quotes” but that’s maybe because pressing <code class="inline">alt + [</code> has become an ingrained behavior when writing a quotation.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Recent reads </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/recent-reads.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/recent-reads</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Syncing Instapaper and my Kindle has been one of the best moves I&#8217;ve made in a long time. I’m reading more of what I want to read, more often. Here’s what I&#8217;ve been reading lately.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/06/26/magazine/my-life-as-an-undocumented-immigrant.html?_r=2&amp;pagewanted=all">My Life as an Undocumented Immigrant</a> – Jose Antonio Vargas</h2>
<p>It’s unlikely you’ve missed this one, but if you have, it’s a great read. Jose Antonio Vargas, a well regarded journalist uncovers himself as an illegal immigrant the US, and explains how he did it.</p>
<h2><a href="http://marcdrummond.com/web-standards/2011/06/20/hell-bad-devices-responsive-web-design-and-web-standards">To hell with bad devices: Responsive web design and web standards</a> – Marc Drummond</h2>
<p>Marc Drummond against device specific design, urging us not to go to great lengths to support poor mobile browsers. IE6 haunted us for so long because we went to great lengths to support it. Let&#8217;s not repeat the same mistakes.</p>
<h2><a href="http://changeobserver.designobserver.com/feature/epiphany-of-an-ocean-swimmer/27548/">Epiphany of an Ocean Swimmer</a> – Barbara Flanagan</h2>
<p>I’ve never owned (or even worn) a wet-suit. I’m convinced it’s time to try.</p>
<h2><a href="http://observersroom.designobserver.com/alexandralange/post/new-apple-hq-1957/28018/">New Apple HQ, 1957</a> – Alexandra Lange</h2>
<p>Is Apple’s plan to build the perfect office building repeating corporate and architectural mistakes we’ve seen many times before? Is this a big missed opportunity for Cupertino?</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.phpied.com/overlooked-optimizations-images/">Overlooked Optimizations: Images</a> – Stoyan Stefanov</h2>
<p>We fuss about code-based front-end optimization, but often neglect our biggest bandwidth hog.</p>
<h2><a href="http://craigmod.com/journal/post_artifact/">Post-Artifact Books and Publishing</a> – Craig Mod</h2>
<p>Digital’s effect on how we produce, distribute and consume content, from one of the best thinkers in the space.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.cityofsound.com/blog/2011/06/on-retail.html">On retail</a> – Dan Hill</h2>
<p>A brilliant look at the current (rather poor) state of retail in Australia, the innovators elsewhere, and potential futures. It touches distribution patterns, fabrication, local economies and localism etc.</p>
<h2><a href="http://the99percent.com/tips/7034/Developing-Your-Creative-Practice-Tips-from-Brian-Eno">Developing Your Creative Practice: Tips from Brian Eno</a> – Scott McDowell</h2>
<p>Exactly as the title says.</p>
<h2><a href="http://observatory.designobserver.com/feature/standard-deviations-types-and-families-in-contemporary-design/26428/">Standard Deviations: Types and Families in Contemporary Design</a> – Paul Shaw</h2>
<p>An interesting critique on the typefaces MoMA selected to feature and add their collection.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Slow motion never gets old </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/slo-mo-never-gets-old.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/slo-mo-never-gets-old</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>(via <a href="http://kottke.org/11/06/slo-mo-cymbal-strike">Kottke</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Native style momentum scrolling to arrive in iOS 5 &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://johanbrook.com/browsers/native-momentum-scrolling-ios-5/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/native-style-momentum-scrolling-to-arrive-in-ios-5</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>It’s great news and more evidence that Apple are willing to lead the way in mobile browser development. <code class="inline">position: fixed</code> and <code class="inline">overflow: scroll</code> are also on their way with iOS 5, but let’s not get excited until Android catches up. Until these handsets enable position fixing and full overflow support we’ll have no choice but to continue to add JavaScript to fake these behaviors.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Topguest on your smartphone </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/topguest-on-your-smartphone.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/topguest-on-your-smartphone</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/topguest-mobile.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>I’ve been working on a mobile optimized version of Topguest and it went live today. Visit <a href="http://topguest.com">topguest.com</a> on your smartphone to take a look.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Project Spartan - Facebook’s Hush-Hush Plan To Take On Apple On Their Own Turf &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/15/facebook-project-spartan/"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/project-spartan</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>I’m not sure I buy into this ‘build in the browser to fuck with Apple’ idea. <a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughts-on-flash/">Steve Jobs evangelizes HTML5 and standards-based development</a> and Apple backs this up by building the the best available mobile browser (which is probably the exact reason Facebook are working with it).</p>
<p>Let’s say Facebook succeeds with “Project Spartan” and becomes a distribution centre for browser based applications. I doubt Apple would be upset by Facebook (a company with unrivaled reach) showcasing the capabilities of Apple’s mobile products. I also doubt that people will stop developing native Apple applications.</p>
<p>If this is a war, it requires Apple to be against the evolution of browser-based application development. I don’t think they are. I think the quality of their browsers is evidence enough for now.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Facebook Analog Research Laboratory </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/facebook-analog-research.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/facebook-analog-research</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/facebook.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>I recently stumbled across the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Facebook-Analog-Research-Laboratory/152917571386966">Facebook Analog Research Laboratory</a>  and I’m really impressed. Working as a designer at a software start-up (if we can call Facebook one) doesn’t usually provoke images of ink, paint, raw materials and hardware.</p>
<p>Although it’s clear that Facebook are currently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/04/27/facebook-acq-hires-daytum/">working to acquire</a> (and <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/09/facebook-sofa/">here</a>) a world class design team, most wouldn’t think of Facebook&#8217;s crisp and minimal design ethos as one that includes decorative practice and paint spills.</p>
<p>It turns out that Facebook (like any big company) use printed materials and physical artifacts for a variety of reasons – events in particular. Outsourcing is expensive, and I’m not just talking about the printing bills, but the administration, the transportation and timing logistics, processing the purchase orders and invoices etc.</p>
<p>Facebook are both saving money, and speeding up the production process. Need some signage for a developer event <em>tonight</em>? Why not design, print and construct them &#8211; right now! It allows the same flexibility and agility we strive to give developers in a start-up environment.</p>
<p>I’m yet to meet a designer that doesn&#8217;t love paper, raw materials and the workshop environment. A workshop like this must also help in attracting (or closing the deal with) versatile design candidates.</p>
<p>But best of all, it encourages, engages, develops and nurtures the companies’ creatives.</p>
<p>Need evidence? <a href="http://www.underconsideration.com/fpo/archives/2011/05/president-barack-obama-at-facebook-tickets.php"><span class="caps">FPO</span></a> profiles the tickets the Facebook team produced in less than 24 for Obama&#8217;s Town Hall event at Facebook’s headquarters.</p>
<p><img src="/images/posts/tickets.jpg" style="margin-left: 0;" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/video/video.php?v=10150096693006777&amp;oid=75877461389&amp;comments">Take a video tour of the Facebook Analog Research Laboratory</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Walt Disney's MultiPlane Camera </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/disneys-multiplane-camera.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/disneys-multiplane-camera</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Innovation and execution. I think I’ll stop in at <a href="http://www.lostweekendvideo.com">Lost Weekend</a> and grab some Goofy cartoons.</p>
<p>(via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2011/06/14/walt-disney-animation">Daring Fireball</a>)</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Fixed positions with JavaScript </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/fixed-positions-with-javascript.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/fixed-positions-with-javascript</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Fixed elements (sidebars in particular) are <a href="http://help.bigcartel.com/articles/22-javascript-ajax">becoming</a> <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/configure/MC723LL/A?mco=MjEyOTY4OTQ">popular</a>. You know those sidebars that wait until the top of window hits them, and they magically stick?</p>
<p>In simple situations (this site for example) <span class="caps">CSS</span> will do the trick. But what if dynamic content at the top of your page changes this calculation (a flash or notification message for example)? Or your header likes to change size?</p>
<p><a href="http://ozanonay.com">Ozan</a> helped me solve this problem, and I thought I&#8217;d share.</p>
<p>We’ll start by selecting said element, calling our custom function, and specifying how far from the top of the page it lives:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="js"><span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;#fixed&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">myFixture</span><span class="p">({</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="mi">20</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre>
</div><p>And our function looks something like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="js"><span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">fn</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">myFixture</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">each</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
    
    <span class="c1">// default css declaration </span>
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">elem</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">css</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;position&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;fixed&#39;</span><span class="p">);</span>
    
    <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">setPosition</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>         
      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">top</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">;</span>
      <span class="c1">// get no of pixels hidden above the the window     </span>
      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">scrollTop</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">window</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">scrollTop</span><span class="p">();</span>    
      <span class="c1">// get elements distance from top of window</span>
      <span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">topBuffer</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="nx">settings</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">topBoundary</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">-</span> <span class="nx">scrollTop</span><span class="p">);</span>
      <span class="c1">// update position if required</span>
      <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">topBuffer</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="p">{</span> <span class="nx">top</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="nx">topBuffer</span> <span class="p">}</span>
      <span class="nx">elem</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">css</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;top&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">top</span><span class="p">);</span>      
    <span class="p">};</span>
        
    <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">window</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">bind</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;scroll&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">setPosition</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="nx">setPosition</span><span class="p">();</span>
  <span class="p">});</span>
<span class="p">};</span>
</code></pre>
</div><p>Let’s revisit our first block of code, and base the calculation on the height of a header element above it:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="js"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">header</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;header&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">header</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">outerHeight</span><span class="p">();</span>
<span class="nx">$</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">&#39;#fixed&#39;</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">myFixture</span><span class="p">({</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="nx">topBoundary</span> <span class="p">});</span>
</code></pre>
</div><p>Another (even more flexible) approach would be to make <code class="default-size">topBoundary</code> equal to the <code class="default-size">.offset.top()</code> of the <code class="default-size">#fixed</code> element on load.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Topguest at Lake Tahoe </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/06/topguest-at-lake-tahoe.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/topguest-at-lake-tahoe</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/tahoe-01.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>The Topguest team took some friends to Lake Tahoe the weekend before last. As you can see, it’s a really beautiful part of the world.</p>
<p><img style="margin-left: 0;" src="/images/posts/tahoe-02.jpg"/><br />
<img style="margin-left: 0; margin-top: 30px" src="/images/posts/tahoe-03.jpg"/></p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A blog in two days with Jekyll &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://blog.topguest.com/2011/04/designing-and-building-a-blog-in-two-days.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/a-blog-in-two-days-with-jekyll</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>A post I wrote over at the Topguest blog on rapid blog development with <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki">Jekyll</a> &ndash; the same platform I built this blog with. If you’re interested in front-end development I think it’s worth a read.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Google drops IE7 &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2011/06/our-plans-to-support-modern-browsers.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/google-drops-ie7</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Great news. As of August 1st Google Apps (including gmail and docs) will drop support for IE7. If Google can do it, so can I.</p>
<blockquote>“As the world moves more to the web, these new browsers are more than just a modern convenience, they are a necessity for what the future holds.”</blockquote>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Anni Albers in the NGA online archive &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://cs.nga.gov.au/Search.cfm?mystartrow=1&realstartrow=1&VIEW_SELECT=1&CREIRN=12177&ORDER_SELECT=1&SHOWROWS=20"/>
        
        <updated>2011-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/06/anni-albers</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/posts/anni-albers.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>Have found some simply stunning Anni Albers (the wife of my favourite artist, Josef Albers) prints at the National Gallery Of Australia.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A new Topguest </title>
        
        
        <link href="http://njmcgee.com/2011/05/a-new-topguest.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/05/a-new-topguest</id>
        <content type="html">
          
           <img src="http://njmcgee.com/images/topguest-devices.jpg"></img>
          
          <p>You might have noticed that things are changing at Topguest. A new design, some subtle but important changes to the application, and we’ve just launched the beginnings of a new mobile web experience.</p>
<p>One of the more dramatic changes is the much brighter color scheme. After applying it to some important layouts I mentioned to the team that we’d “turned the lights on”. This stuck with me, as I worked through problems unrelated to color or shade, and I hope it shows. We hope the new (and upcoming) changes, bring clarity, ease of use, and lots more points!</p>
<p>Things aren’t slowing anytime soon. We’re adding programs and new locations every day, and be sure to visit <a href="http://topguest.com">http://topguest.com</a> on your mobile browser. We’re regularly adding mobile optimized functionality so you can manage your points, and find locations on the go.</p>
<p>Any feedback? <a href="mailto:nathan@topguest.com">Get in touch</a>.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Our vision for the future of loyalty &#x219D;</title>
        
        
        <link href="http://blog.topguest.com/2011/05/the-future-of-loyalty.html"/>
        
        <updated>2011-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
        <id>njmcgee.com:/2011/05/the-future-of-loyalty</id>
        <content type="html">
          
          <p>Our <span class="caps">CEO</span> Geoff on the business we do at Topguest.</p>
          
        </content>
        <author>
            <name></name>
            <uri></uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    
</feed>